<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<patent-document ucid="EP-2693861-A1" country="EP" doc-number="2693861" kind="A1" date="20140212" family-id="45816272" file-reference-id="311175" date-produced="20180827" status="corrected" lang="EN"><bibliographic-data><publication-reference fvid="147149706" ucid="EP-2693861-A1"><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>2693861</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20140212</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></publication-reference><application-reference ucid="EP-12718032-A" is-representative="NO"><document-id mxw-id="PAPP155572148" load-source="docdb" format="epo"><country>EP</country><doc-number>12718032</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20120328</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id><document-id mxw-id="PAPP191081523" load-source="docdb" format="original"><country>EP</country><doc-number>12718032.1</doc-number><date>20120328</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></application-reference><priority-claims><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC141366453" ucid="CZ-20110187-A" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>CZ</country><doc-number>20110187</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20110404</date></document-id></priority-claim><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC141366454" ucid="CZ-2012000028-W" linkage-type="W" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>CZ</country><doc-number>2012000028</doc-number><kind>W</kind><date>20120328</date></document-id></priority-claim></priority-claims><technical-data><classifications-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL2007787767" load-source="docdb">A01B  21/08        20060101AFI20121023BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL2007787768" load-source="docdb">A01B  25/00        20060101ALI20121023BHEP        </classification-ipcr></classifications-ipcr><classifications-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL2008518034" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">A01B  21/086       20130101 LI20130921BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL2008519866" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">A01B  25/00        20130101 LI20130921BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL2008527029" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">A01B  49/02        20130101 FI20130921BHEP        </classification-cpc></classifications-cpc><invention-title mxw-id="PT133343288" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office">ERDBODENBEHANDLUNGSMASCHINE</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT133343289" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office">SOIL TREATMENT MACHINE</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT133343290" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office">MACHINE DE TRAITEMENT DE SOL</invention-title></technical-data><parties><applicants><applicant mxw-id="PPAR949295364" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>FARMET A S</last-name><address><country>CZ</country></address></addressbook></applicant><applicant mxw-id="PPAR949313311" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>FARMET A.S.</last-name></addressbook></applicant><applicant mxw-id="PPAR948491656" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Farmet A.S.</last-name><iid>101342581</iid><address><street>Jirinková 276</street><city>55203 Ceská Skalice</city><country>CZ</country></address></addressbook></applicant></applicants><inventors><inventor mxw-id="PPAR949306753" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>NYC MICHAL</last-name><address><country>CZ</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR949310643" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>NYC, Michal</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR948496627" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>NYC, Michal</last-name><address><street>Lhota 273</street><city>54941 Cervený Kostelec</city><country>CZ</country></address></addressbook></inventor></inventors><agents><agent mxw-id="PPAR948490037" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Skoda, Milan</last-name><iid>100051024</iid><address><street>Nahoranska 308</street><city>549 01 Nove Mesto nad Metuji</city><country>CZ</country></address></addressbook></agent></agents></parties><international-convention-data><pct-or-regional-filing-data ucid="CZ-2012000028-W"><document-id><country>CZ</country><doc-number>2012000028</doc-number><kind>W</kind><date>20120328</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></pct-or-regional-filing-data><pct-or-regional-publishing-data ucid="WO-2012136173-A1"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>2012136173</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20121011</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></pct-or-regional-publishing-data><designated-states><ep-contracting-states><country mxw-id="DS554603242" load-source="docdb">AL</country><country mxw-id="DS554595670" load-source="docdb">AT</country><country mxw-id="DS554603243" load-source="docdb">BE</country><country mxw-id="DS554546342" load-source="docdb">BG</country><country mxw-id="DS554525856" load-source="docdb">CH</country><country mxw-id="DS554609121" load-source="docdb">CY</country><country mxw-id="DS554595671" load-source="docdb">CZ</country><country mxw-id="DS554603244" load-source="docdb">DE</country><country mxw-id="DS554609122" load-source="docdb">DK</country><country mxw-id="DS554609123" load-source="docdb">EE</country><country mxw-id="DS554611798" load-source="docdb">ES</country><country mxw-id="DS554546343" load-source="docdb">FI</country><country mxw-id="DS554546344" load-source="docdb">FR</country><country mxw-id="DS554603249" load-source="docdb">GB</country><country mxw-id="DS554609124" load-source="docdb">GR</country><country mxw-id="DS554603250" load-source="docdb">HR</country><country mxw-id="DS554595672" load-source="docdb">HU</country><country mxw-id="DS554525857" load-source="docdb">IE</country><country mxw-id="DS554609125" load-source="docdb">IS</country><country mxw-id="DS554546345" load-source="docdb">IT</country><country mxw-id="DS554609126" load-source="docdb">LI</country><country mxw-id="DS554600755" load-source="docdb">LT</country><country mxw-id="DS554617309" load-source="docdb">LU</country><country mxw-id="DS554600756" load-source="docdb">LV</country><country mxw-id="DS554600761" load-source="docdb">MC</country><country mxw-id="DS554617310" load-source="docdb">MK</country><country mxw-id="DS554617311" load-source="docdb">MT</country><country mxw-id="DS554603251" load-source="docdb">NL</country><country mxw-id="DS554546346" load-source="docdb">NO</country><country mxw-id="DS554600762" load-source="docdb">PL</country><country mxw-id="DS554525858" load-source="docdb">PT</country><country mxw-id="DS554603252" load-source="docdb">RO</country><country mxw-id="DS554525863" load-source="docdb">RS</country><country mxw-id="DS554600763" load-source="docdb">SE</country><country mxw-id="DS554611799" load-source="docdb">SI</country><country mxw-id="DS554546347" load-source="docdb">SK</country><country mxw-id="DS554600764" load-source="docdb">SM</country><country mxw-id="DS554609127" load-source="docdb">TR</country></ep-contracting-states></designated-states></international-convention-data><office-specific-data><eptags><ep-no-a-document-published>*</ep-no-a-document-published></eptags></office-specific-data></bibliographic-data><abstract mxw-id="PA100919547" ref-ucid="WO-2012136173-A1" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><p num="0000">The soil treatment machine, in particular the machine that includes two transverse rows (8,9) of concaved plates (5,5'), mounted in series and installed on the connecting frame (2,2'), while the concaved plates (5,5') of the first row (8) are situated sideways forwards and directed to one side and concaved plates (5') of the second row (9) are situated sideways forwards and directed to the other side, and individual concaved plates (5,5') in each row (8,9) are situated in parallel on independent support arms (4,4'), to which they are loosely and pivotally connected to by bearings, and there is a deflection board (14,14') situated behind at least one of the rows (8,9) of concaved plates (5,5'), and this deflection board (14,14') is formed as compact and solid, while on its bottom side it is provided with cuts in the machine width direction, and these cuts (18) go up to min. 50% of its height, and the area ratio of cuts (18) against the total area of the deflection board (14,14') up to the height of cuts (18) is greater than 55%.</p></abstract><abstract mxw-id="PA101180726" ref-ucid="WO-2012136173-A1" lang="EN" source="national office" load-source="docdb"><p>The soil treatment machine, in particular the machine that includes two transverse rows (8,9) of concaved plates (5,5'), mounted in series and installed on the connecting frame (2,2'), while the concaved plates (5,5') of the first row (8) are situated sideways forwards and directed to one side and concaved plates (5') of the second row (9) are situated sideways forwards and directed to the other side, and individual concaved plates (5,5') in each row (8,9) are situated in parallel on independent support arms (4,4'), to which they are loosely and pivotally connected to by bearings, and there is a deflection board (14,14') situated behind at least one of the rows (8,9) of concaved plates (5,5'), and this deflection board (14,14') is formed as compact and solid, while on its bottom side it is provided with cuts in the machine width direction, and these cuts (18) go up to min. 50% of its height, and the area ratio of cuts (18) against the total area of the deflection board (14,14') up to the height of cuts (18) is greater than 55%.</p></abstract><abstract mxw-id="PA100919548" ref-ucid="WO-2012136173-A1" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office"><p num="0000">L'invention porte sur une machine de traitement de sol, en particulier sur une machine qui comprend deux rangées transversales (8, 9) de plaques concaves (5, 5'), montées en série et installées sur le châssis de liaison (2, 2'), tandis que les plaques concaves (5, 5') de la première rangée (8) sont situés latéralement vers l'avant et dirigés vers un côté, et que les plaques concaves (5') de la seconde rangée (9) sont situés latéralement vers l'avant et dirigées vers l'autre côté, et des plaques concaves individuelles (5, 5') dans chaque rangée (8, 9) étant situés en parallèle sur des bras de support indépendants (4, 4'), sur lesquels elles sont reliées de façon lâche et pivotante par des paliers, et une plaque d'infléchissement (14, 14') étant présente, située derrière au moins l'une des rangées (8, 9) de plaques concaves (5, 5'), et cette plaque d'infléchissement (14, 14'), étant formée de façon à être compacte et pleine, tandis que, sur son côté inférieur, elle comporte des entailles dans la direction de largeur de la machine, et ces entailles (18) s'étendant au minimum jusqu'à 50% de sa hauteur, et le rapport de surface des entailles (18) par rapport à la surface totale de la plaque d'infléchissement (14, 14') jusqu'à la hauteur des entailles (18) étant supérieur à 55%.</p></abstract><abstract mxw-id="PA101180727" ref-ucid="WO-2012136173-A1" lang="FR" source="national office" load-source="docdb"><p>L'invention porte sur une machine de traitement de sol, en particulier sur une machine qui comprend deux rangées transversales (8, 9) de plaques concaves (5, 5'), montées en série et installées sur le châssis de liaison (2, 2'), tandis que les plaques concaves (5, 5') de la première rangée (8) sont situés latéralement vers l'avant et dirigés vers un côté, et que les plaques concaves (5') de la seconde rangée (9) sont situés latéralement vers l'avant et dirigées vers l'autre côté, et des plaques concaves individuelles (5, 5') dans chaque rangée (8, 9) étant situés en parallèle sur des bras de support indépendants (4, 4'), sur lesquels elles sont reliées de façon lâche et pivotante par des paliers, et une plaque d'infléchissement (14, 14') étant présente, située derrière au moins l'une des rangées (8, 9) de plaques concaves (5, 5'), et cette plaque d'infléchissement (14, 14'), étant formée de façon à être compacte et pleine, tandis que, sur son côté inférieur, elle comporte des entailles dans la direction de largeur de la machine, et ces entailles (18) s'étendant au minimum jusqu'à 50% de sa hauteur, et le rapport de surface des entailles (18) par rapport à la surface totale de la plaque d'infléchissement (14, 14') jusqu'à la hauteur des entailles (18) étant supérieur à 55%.</p></abstract><description mxw-id="PDES51854869" ref-ucid="WO-2012136173-A1" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="2"/>--><p id="p0001" num="0001"> Soil Treatment Machine </p><p id="p0002" num="0002">Technical Field </p><p id="p0003" num="0003">The invention relates to a soil treatment machine, in particular the machine including at least two transverse rows of concave plates with deflection boards situated behind them in driving direction. </p><p id="p0004" num="0004">Background Art </p><p id="p0005" num="0005">There are currently many soil treatment machines on the market, with independently fitted plates in two usually parallel rows perpendicular to driving direction. Concaved plates are in each row fitted on independent brackets, where plate planes usually form an open angle with the soil surface, while two basic technical solutions can be distinguished. Concaved plates are pivotally attached to brackets with their convex or concave side. Each of the solutions mentioned offers certain advantages and disadvantages. If the concaved plates are attached to brackets with their convex side, the machine with given plate diameters achieves less operating depth, which can be considered a disadvantage. The advantage on the contrary is that the bearings of plates are with respect to the plate angle protected, mainly in the rear row of plates, against the soil flying off from the front plates, which reduces demands on the technical solution of sealing and increases durability of plate bearings in the rear row. </p><p id="p0006" num="0006"> There is also another solution noted, under which the plates are attached to brackets by their concave side. The advantage of this technical solution is that greater operating depth can be achieved with given plate diameters. Its disadvantage is that plate bearings, mainly in the rear row of plates, are exposed to direct soil flow flying off from the front row of plates. This essentially increases mechanical stress of bearing seals and reduces their durability. On that score, deflection devices are used that regulate the soil flow flying off from plates, mainly between the first and second row of plates, so that the stress of bearing seals of the second row of disks is reduced. Another reason for using deflection devices is their positive impact on the soil treatment quality, breaking clods, and ground levelling. From this point of view it is beneficial to use deflection devices behind both plate rows. The disadvantage of 
<!-- EPO <DP n="3"/>-->
 deflection devices is certain reduction of material throughput (soil and plant residues) between the first and second plate row, and also increased risk of soil sticking on deflection devices and possible machine jams. </p><p id="p0007" num="0007"> The patent WO 2005/077139 describes a deflection device, which by its structure reduces mentioned risks and which is suitable for use in machines with concave plate attachment, where it provides sufficient protection of bearings of the second row of concaved plates. Neither this solution however removes the problem of reduced throughput for the soil and plant residues and certain risk of sticking and clogging under worse soil conditions. </p><p id="p0008" num="0008"> The interesting solution is shown in the patent EP 1 300 060 that as a deflection device uses flexible tips similar to tips of light harrows. The advantage of this solution is a great throughput for the soil and plant residues and practically low risk of sticking and clogging. By its structure, this deflection device is however suitable for machines with convex plate attachment, since it does not provide sufficient protection of bearings in the second row of plates against soil flying off from the first row of plates. According to practical experience, this deflection device has many disadvantages. For good functionality of the device and to achieve higher operating speed of the machine, it is usually necessary to set the tips of the deflection device to a position at the maximum distance form the row of plates, which are to regulate the soil flow behind. With this setup, tip ends of the deflection device will get to a close distance of the second raw of plates, mainly behind the first row of plates with respect to their density. Due to soil and stones striking the flexible tips, they deflect significantly and subsequently collide with the rear row of plates. In practice, it causes frequent damage to deflection device tips and their optimal setup cannot be always achieved, or at the price of the risk of damage only. Another considerable disadvantage of this solution is its relatively higher technical complicacy, higher production demands, and higher factory price. </p><p id="p0009" num="0009"> It is apparent from the state of the art mentioned, that the current state shows many disadvantages. </p><p id="p0010" num="0010"> The objective of the invention is a structure of the soil treatment machine that will eliminate disadvantages above. 
<!-- EPO <DP n="4"/>-->
 Disclosure of the Invention </p><p id="p0011" num="0011">Disadvantages mentioned are to a great extent eliminated and objectives are met with the soil treatment machine, mainly the machine including at least two rows of concaved plates installed in series on the connecting frame, while concaved plates are positioned sideways to driving direction, i.e. concaved plates of the first raw are directed forward to one side, sideways to driving direction, and concaved plates of the second raw are directed forward to the other side, sideways to driving direction, and individual concaved plates in each raw are situated beside each other on independent support arms, which they are loosely and pivotally coupled with, and there is at least one deflection board behind at least one row of concaved plates in its entire operating width, according to the invention, the merit of which is that the deflection board is formed as compact and solid, provided with cuts on its bottom side in the machine width direction, and these cuts go up to min. 50% of its height, and the area ratio of cuts against the total area of the deflection board up to the height of cuts is greater than 55%. </p><p id="p0012" num="0012"> Deflection boards are situated so that part of the soil flying off from concaved plates strikes the boards; the soil crumbles and its flow is more even. Cuts in boards are large enough to avoid undesired sticking of the soil or clogging, and they are made from the material with relatively low flexibility such as steel or solid rigid plastic. Arrangement of deflection boards according to the innovation is beneficial for use in both, machines with swivel attachment of concaved plates on their concave side, where the bearings in the rear raw of plates can be threatened by excessive stress caused by soil flying off from the front plates, and machines with swivel attachment of concaved plates on their convex side. </p><p id="p0013" num="0013"> It is beneficial, if the cuts on the deflection board have rectangular, semicircular, half-oval, parabolic or trapezoid shape, or combination of those. </p><p id="p0014" num="0014"> It is also beneficial, if the deflection board is attached directly to the connecting frame or the cross bar that is fixed to the connecting frame or directly to the frame of the rear compacting and copying device, or it is attached to the connecting frame, cross bars, frame of the rear compacting and copying device using at least one fixture or using an inserted frame. </p><p id="p0015" num="0015"> The deflection board is preferably flat or curved. Its curve improves regulation of the soil flow and also increases the overall rigidity of the deflection board. 
<!-- EPO <DP n="5"/>-->
 It is beneficial, if part of the board with cuts forms an angle (a) with the soil surface from 0 to 120°, which again optimizes the soil flow. </p><p id="p0016" num="0016"> It is also beneficial, if the attachment of the deflection board to the connecting frame or the cross bar or to the frame of the rear compacting and copying device is adjustable. This allows adjust optimally the position of the deflection board with respect to soil conditions. </p><p id="p0017" num="0017"> In its beneficial version, at least one of the deflection boards is connected with a roller ensuring its depth conduct, and this roller ensures accurate altitudinal conduct of deflection boards against the soil surface. </p><p id="p0018" num="0018"> Deflection boards are usually formed as compact components corresponding by their width with the operating width of the machine. The deflection board might be also sectional, when the width of individual sections corresponds with the operating width of individual machine sections foldable for transport purposes. This version enables easier and safer transport of the whole machine for soil treatment on public roads. </p><p id="p0019" num="0019"> For optimum functionality of the soil treatment machine it is beneficial if the support arms of concaved plates are fitted with flexible components enabling individual adjustment of the operating depth of each concaved plate or providing fixed position of concaved plates by its initial stress, and in case of overload they allow deflection of plates upwards and backwards. </p><p id="p0020" num="0020"> The deflection plate under the innovation is rigid and inflexible, preferably made from hardened steel. High rigidity of the deflection board improves significantly the effect of crushing the clods flying off from plates and striking deflection boards. High rigidity of the deflection board also enables its positioning at the maximum distance behind previous row of concaved plates, to the close distance of the next row of concaved plates or the roller, without the risk of mutual collision and damage. This can significantly increase the operating speed of the machine and reduce the risk of clogging. The deflection board might be located high enough under the soil surface and at the sufficient distance from the previous raw of concaved plates, so the risk of its damage by large stone or other solid barrier from the previous raw of concaved plates is significantly eliminated. On that score, the deflection device does not have to be equipped with any safeguard against overload. 
<!-- EPO <DP n="6"/>-->
 Review of figures in the drawing </p><p id="p0021" num="0021">The innovation will be explained better using a drawing, in which Fig. 1 shows the soil treatment machine in an axonometric view, Fig. 2 shows the soil treatment machine in a side view, Fig. 3 shows a detail view of deflection board attachment, and Fig. 4 shows a detail view of the deflection board. </p><p id="p0022" num="0022">Description of example </p><p id="p0023" num="0023">Soil treatment machine 1 (Fig. 1 , Fig. 2) is equipped with a connecting frame 2,2<sup>'</sup> with cross bars 3,3<sup>'</sup>. On cross bars, independent arms 4,4<sup>'</sup> are pivoted, on which individual concaved plates 5,5<sup>'</sup> are pivoted. Swivel attachment of plates is formed by bearing 6. Concaved plates 5, 5<sup>'</sup> are maintained in required operating position using flexible components 7. According to rigidity of flexible components, concaved plates 5,5<sup>'</sup> can be fixed firmly in the required position or oscillate smoothly according to the resistance of the soil treated. </p><p id="p0024" num="0024"> The soil treatment machine includes two transverse rows 8,9 of concaved plates 5,5<sup>'</sup>, mounted in series and installed on the connecting frame 2,2<sup>'</sup>. The front section of the soil treatment machine contains concaved plates 5 of the front row 8 of concaved plates 5. Concaved plates of the front row are situated sideways to driving direction and directed by their concave surfaces to the right in driving direction. The rear section of the soil treatment machine 1 includes concaved plates 5<sup>'</sup> of the rear row 9 of concaved plates 5<sup>'</sup>. Concaved plates 5<sup>'</sup> of the rear row 9 are situated sideways to driving direction and directed by their concave surfaces to the left in driving direction. </p><p id="p0025" num="0025"> The connecting frame 2,2<sup>'</sup> is pivotally attached to the frame 0 of the rear compacting and copying device H . This device is designed as a roller consisting of two rows of tires, or as a ramming roller. Mutual position of the connecting frame 2,2<sup>'</sup> and the frame 10 of the rear compacting and copying device can be adjusted using a hydraulic cylinder 12 and adjustable retainers 13. Using adjustable retainers 13, appropriate position of the connecting frame 2,2<sup>'</sup> and the frame 10 can be set for the operating position of the machine and thus achieve accurate depth conduct of the front row 8 of concaved plates 5 and the rear row 9 of concaved plates 5<sup>'</sup>. The rear 
<!-- EPO <DP n="7"/>-->
 compacting and copying device H enables machine transport on public roads after hydraulic cylinder 12 release. </p><p id="p0026" num="0026"> Behind each row 8,9 of concaved plates 5,5<sup>'</sup>, there is one deflection board 14,14' situated in its entire operating width (Fig. 3, Fig. 4) that is formed as compact and solid, provided with parallel cuts 8 on the bottom side in the direction of the machine width 18 that reach min. up to 66 % of its height, and the area ratio cuts 18 and the total deflection board 14,14<sup>'</sup> area up to the height of cuts 18 is higher than 55%. </p><p id="p0027" num="0027"> Cuts 18 in the deflection board 14.-14<sup>'</sup> (Fig. 4) have conic shape, alternatively trapezoid, rectangular, semicircular, half-oval, parabolic shape, or combination of those shapes. </p><p id="p0028" num="0028"> First deflection board 14 (Fig. 1 , Fig. 2) is by two fixtures 15 attached in its upper section 17 to the cross bar 3,3<sup>'</sup>. </p><p id="p0029" num="0029"> Second deflection board 14<sup>'</sup> (Fig. 1 , Fig. 2) is by two fixtures 16, attached in its upper section 17 to the frame 10 of the rear compacting and copying device JM . </p><p id="p0030" num="0030"> Alternatively, deflection boards 14,14<sup>'</sup> might be attached directly to the connecting frame 2,2<sup>'</sup> or the cross bar 3,3<sup>'</sup> that is fixed to the connecting frame 2,2<sup>'</sup> or directly to the frame 10 of the rear compacting and copying device H, or they might be attached to the connecting frame 2,2<sup>'</sup>, cross bar 3,3<sup>'</sup>, frame 10 of the rear compacting and copying device H using an inserted frame not shown here. </p><p id="p0031" num="0031"> Alternatively, the attachment of deflection boards 14,14<sup>'</sup> to the connecting frame 2,2' or the cross bar 3,3<sup>'</sup> or the frame 10 of the rear compacting and copying device H might be adjustable. </p><p id="p0032" num="0032"> Deflection boards 14,14<sup>'</sup> are flat. Alternatively, they might be curved. Part of the deflection bards 14,14' with cuts 18 forms an angle (a) with the soil surface of 80°. </p><p id="p0033" num="0033"> At least one of the deflection boards 14,14<sup>'</sup> is connected with the roller providing its depth conduct (not shown). </p><p id="p0034" num="0034"> Deflection board 14,14' might be alternatively sectional, and the length of individual sections corresponds with the operating width of individual sections of the machine that are foldable for transport purposes. </p><p id="p0035" num="0035"> The support arms 4,4<sup>'</sup> of concaved plates 5,5<sup>'</sup> are provided with flexible components 7 enabling individual adjustment of the operating depth of each 
<!-- EPO <DP n="8"/>-->
 concaved plate; or by their initial stress they ensure the position of concaved plates and in case of overload enable deflection of plates upwards and backwards. </p><p id="p0036" num="0036">Industrial applicability </p><p id="p0037" num="0037">The soil treatment machine under the innovation can be used for highly efficient soil treatment. 
</p></description><claims mxw-id="PCLM45499702" ref-ucid="WO-2012136173-A1" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><claim-statement><!-- EPO <DP n="9"/>-->Patent claims </claim-statement><claim id="clm-0001" num="1"><claim-text>1. The soil treatment machine, in particular the machine that includes two transverse rows (8,9) of concaved plates (5,5<sup>'</sup>), mounted in series and installed on the connecting frame (2,2<sup>'</sup>), while the concaved plates (5,5<sup>'</sup>) of the first row (8) are situated sideways forwards and directed to one side and concaved plates (5<sup>'</sup>) of the second row (9) are situated sideways forwards and directed to the other side, and individual concaved plates (5,5<sup>'</sup>) in each row (8,9) are situated in parallel on independent support arms (4,4<sup>'</sup>), to which they are loosely and pivotally connected to by bearings, and there is a deflection board (14,14 ) situated behind at least one of the rows (8,9) of concaved plates (5,5 ), and this deflection board (14,14<sup>'</sup>) characterized by the fact that deflection board (14,14<sup>'</sup>) is formed as compact and solid, while on its bottom side it is provided with cuts (18) in the machine width direction, and these cuts (18) go up to minimally 50% of its height, and the area ratio of cuts (18) against the total area of the deflection board (14,14<sup>'</sup>) up to the height of cuts (18) is greater than 55%. </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0002" num="2"><claim-text> 2. The soil treatment machine under the claim 1 characterized by the fact that the cuts (18) of the deflection board (14,14<sup>'</sup>) have conic, rectangular, semicircular, half-oval, parabolic or trapezoid shape, or combination of those. </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0003" num="3"><claim-text> 3. The soil treatment machine under any previous claim characterized by the fact that the deflection board (14,14<sup>'</sup>) is attached directly to the connecting frame (2,2<sup>'</sup>) or the cross bar (3,3<sup>'</sup>), which is attached to the connecting frame (2,2<sup>'</sup>) or directly to the frame (10) of the rear compacting and copying device (11), or it is attached to the connecting frame (2,2<sup>'</sup>) or the cross bar (3,3 ), to the frame (10) of the rear compacting and copying device (11) using at least one fixture (15,16) or using an inserted frame. </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0004" num="4"><claim-text> 4. The soil treatment machine under any previous claim characterized by the fact that the deflection board (14,14<sup>'</sup>) is flat or curved. </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0005" num="5"><claim-text> 5. The soil treatment machine under any previous claim characterized by the fact that part of the deflection board (14,14<sup>'</sup>) with cuts (18) forms an angle (a) with the soil surface from 0° to 120°. <!-- EPO <DP n="10"/>--> </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0006" num="6"><claim-text>6. The soil treatment machine under any previous claim characterized by the fact that the attachment of the deflection board (14,14<sup>'</sup>) to the connecting frame (2,2<sup>'</sup>) or the cross bar (3,3<sup>'</sup>), or the frame (10) of the rear compacting and copying device is adjustable. </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0007" num="7"><claim-text> 7. The soil treatment machine under any previous claim characterized by the fact that at least one of the deflection boards (14,14<sup>'</sup>) is connected with the roller providing its depth conduct. </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0008" num="8"><claim-text> 8. The soil treatment machine under any previous claim characterized by the fact that the deflection board (14,14<sup>'</sup>) is sectional, and the width of individual sections corresponds with the operating width of individual machine sections that are foldable for transport purposes. </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0009" num="9"><claim-text> 9. The soil treatment machine under any previous claim characterized by the fact that support arms (4,4<sup>'</sup>) of concaved plates (5,5<sup>'</sup>) are provided with flexible components (7) enabling individual permitted accommodation of the operating depth of each concaved plate, or by their initial stress provide fixed position of concaved plates, and in case of overload enable deflection of concaved plates upwards and backwards. <!-- EPO <DP n="11"/>--> </claim-text><claim-text>List of Reference Marks </claim-text><claim-text>1 Soil treatment machine </claim-text><claim-text> 2,2<sup>'</sup> Connecting frame</claim-text><claim-text>3,3<sup>'</sup> Cross bar </claim-text><claim-text> 4,4<sup>'</sup> Independent arm </claim-text><claim-text> 5,5<sup>'</sup> Concaved plate </claim-text><claim-text> 6 Bearing </claim-text><claim-text> 7 Flexible component</claim-text><claim-text>8 Row I </claim-text><claim-text> 9 Row II </claim-text><claim-text> 10 Frame </claim-text><claim-text> 11 Compacting and copying device</claim-text><claim-text>12 Hydraulic cylinder</claim-text><claim-text>13 Adjustable retainer</claim-text><claim-text>14,14 <sup>'</sup> Deflection board</claim-text><claim-text>15 Fixture I </claim-text><claim-text> 16 Fixture II </claim-text><claim-text> 17 Upper section </claim-text><claim-text> 18 Cutout </claim-text></claim></claims><copyright>User acknowledges that Fairview Research LLC and its third party providers retain all right, title and interest in and to this xml under applicable copyright laws.  User acquires no ownership rights to this xml including but not limited to its format.  User hereby accepts the terms and conditions of the Licence Agreement</copyright></patent-document>
