<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<patent-document ucid="EP-2693869-A1" country="EP" doc-number="2693869" kind="A1" date="20140212" family-id="46851746" file-reference-id="271485" date-produced="20180827" status="corrected" lang="EN"><bibliographic-data><publication-reference fvid="147149698" ucid="EP-2693869-A1"><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>2693869</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20140212</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></publication-reference><application-reference ucid="EP-12768566-A" is-representative="NO"><document-id mxw-id="PAPP155572140" load-source="docdb" format="epo"><country>EP</country><doc-number>12768566</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20120403</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id><document-id mxw-id="PAPP220443904" load-source="docdb" format="original"><country>EP</country><doc-number>12768566.7</doc-number><date>20120403</date></document-id></application-reference><priority-claims><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC141366438" ucid="DK-2012050103-W" linkage-type="W" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>DK</country><doc-number>2012050103</doc-number><kind>W</kind><date>20120403</date></document-id></priority-claim><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC176977157" ucid="DK-PA201170165-A" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>DK</country><doc-number>PA201170165</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20110407</date></document-id></priority-claim></priority-claims><technical-data><classifications-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL2093536792" load-source="docdb">A01K   1/02        20060101AFI20140703BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL2093538426" load-source="docdb">A01K   1/00        20060101ALI20140703BHEP        </classification-ipcr></classifications-ipcr><classifications-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL2008529362" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">A01K   1/0209      20130101 FI20121114BHEP        </classification-cpc></classifications-cpc><invention-title mxw-id="PT133343264" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office">STALL FÜR HAUSTIERE, VORZUGSWEISE SÄUE, MIT EINER ELASTISCHEN VERBINDUNGSSTANGE</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT133343265" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office">A STALL FOR DOMESTIC ANIMALS, PREFERABLY SOWS, WITH A RESILIENT CONNECTING ROD</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT133343266" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office">STALLE POUR ANIMAUX DOMESTIQUES, DE PRÉFÉRENCE POUR TRUIES, AVEC TIGE DE LIAISON ÉLASTIQUE</invention-title></technical-data><parties><applicants><applicant mxw-id="PPAR949305148" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>EGEBJERG INTERNAT A S</last-name><address><country>DK</country></address></addressbook></applicant><applicant mxw-id="PPAR949290915" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>EGEBJERG INTERNATIONAL A/S</last-name></addressbook></applicant><applicant mxw-id="PPAR948491744" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Egebjerg International A/S</last-name><iid>101342983</iid><address><street>Egebjerg Hovedgade 27</street><city>4500 Nykobing SJ</city><country>DK</country></address></addressbook></applicant></applicants><inventors><inventor mxw-id="PPAR949290895" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>RASMUSSEN HENRIK</last-name><address><country>DK</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR949304616" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>RASMUSSEN, HENRIK</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR948491824" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>RASMUSSEN, HENRIK</last-name><address><street>Egebjerg Hovedgade 25</street><city>DK-4500 Nykøbing Sjælland</city><country>DK</country></address></addressbook></inventor></inventors><agents><agent mxw-id="PPAR948495988" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Nielsen, Leif</last-name><suffix>et al</suffix><iid>100029535</iid><address><street>Patrade A/S Fredens Torv 3A</street><city>8000 Aarhus C</city><country>DK</country></address></addressbook></agent></agents></parties><international-convention-data><pct-or-regional-filing-data ucid="DK-2012050103-W"><document-id><country>DK</country><doc-number>2012050103</doc-number><kind>W</kind><date>20120403</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></pct-or-regional-filing-data><pct-or-regional-publishing-data ucid="WO-2012136216-A1"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>2012136216</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20121011</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></pct-or-regional-publishing-data><designated-states><ep-contracting-states><country mxw-id="DS554595140" load-source="docdb">AL</country><country mxw-id="DS554611556" load-source="docdb">AT</country><country mxw-id="DS554595141" load-source="docdb">BE</country><country mxw-id="DS554603031" load-source="docdb">BG</country><country mxw-id="DS554600600" load-source="docdb">CH</country><country mxw-id="DS554617153" load-source="docdb">CY</country><country mxw-id="DS554611561" load-source="docdb">CZ</country><country mxw-id="DS554595142" load-source="docdb">DE</country><country mxw-id="DS554617154" load-source="docdb">DK</country><country mxw-id="DS554617155" load-source="docdb">EE</country><country mxw-id="DS554546304" load-source="docdb">ES</country><country mxw-id="DS554603032" load-source="docdb">FI</country><country mxw-id="DS554603033" load-source="docdb">FR</country><country mxw-id="DS554595143" load-source="docdb">GB</country><country mxw-id="DS554617156" load-source="docdb">GR</country><country mxw-id="DS554595144" load-source="docdb">HR</country><country mxw-id="DS554611562" load-source="docdb">HU</country><country mxw-id="DS554600601" load-source="docdb">IE</country><country mxw-id="DS554617157" load-source="docdb">IS</country><country mxw-id="DS554603034" load-source="docdb">IT</country><country mxw-id="DS554617158" load-source="docdb">LI</country><country mxw-id="DS554608933" load-source="docdb">LT</country><country mxw-id="DS554611563" load-source="docdb">LU</country><country mxw-id="DS554608934" load-source="docdb">LV</country><country mxw-id="DS554608935" load-source="docdb">MC</country><country mxw-id="DS554525812" load-source="docdb">MK</country><country mxw-id="DS554525813" load-source="docdb">MT</country><country mxw-id="DS554546305" load-source="docdb">NL</country><country mxw-id="DS554611564" load-source="docdb">NO</country><country mxw-id="DS554525814" load-source="docdb">PL</country><country mxw-id="DS554617159" load-source="docdb">PT</country><country mxw-id="DS554546306" load-source="docdb">RO</country><country mxw-id="DS554617160" load-source="docdb">RS</country><country mxw-id="DS554525815" load-source="docdb">SE</country><country mxw-id="DS554595145" load-source="docdb">SI</country><country mxw-id="DS554611653" load-source="docdb">SK</country><country mxw-id="DS554525816" load-source="docdb">SM</country><country mxw-id="DS554600602" load-source="docdb">TR</country></ep-contracting-states></designated-states></international-convention-data><office-specific-data><eptags><ep-no-a-document-published>*</ep-no-a-document-published></eptags></office-specific-data></bibliographic-data><abstract mxw-id="PA100920405" ref-ucid="WO-2012136216-A1" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><p num="0000">A stall (1) for domestic animals, preferably sows. The stall comprises a front gate (2) and a feeding trough (3) in the front end (4) of the stall (1) and a rear gate (5) at the rear end of the stall (6). The front gate (2) is suspended so that it can pivot about a first axis (7) and arranged to prevent access by the animal to the feeding trough (3) if the front gate is in a closed state. The stall comprises a displacable connection device (9) connecting the front gate (2) with the rear gate (5) such that opening, respectively closing, of the one gate forces the other gate to close, respectively open. The connection device (9) comprises an elastic element (17) for elastic change ofthe length of the connection device (9). For example, the connection device comprises a resilient telescopic rod.</p></abstract><abstract mxw-id="PA101181404" ref-ucid="WO-2012136216-A1" lang="EN" source="national office" load-source="docdb"><p>A stall (1) for domestic animals, preferably sows. The stall comprises a front gate (2) and a feeding trough (3) in the front end (4) of the stall (1) and a rear gate (5) at the rear end of the stall (6). The front gate (2) is suspended so that it can pivot about a first axis (7) and arranged to prevent access by the animal to the feeding trough (3) if the front gate is in a closed state. The stall comprises a displacable connection device (9) connecting the front gate (2) with the rear gate (5) such that opening, respectively closing, of the one gate forces the other gate to close, respectively open. The connection device (9) comprises an elastic element (17) for elastic change ofthe length of the connection device (9). For example, the connection device comprises a resilient telescopic rod.</p></abstract><abstract mxw-id="PA100920406" ref-ucid="WO-2012136216-A1" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office"><p num="0000">L'invention concerne une stalle (1) pour animaux domestiques, de préférence des truies. La stalle comprend une porte avant (2) et une ouverture d'amenée (3) dans l'extrémité avant (4) de la stalle (1) et une porte arrière (5) à l'extrémité arrière de la stalle (6). La porte avant (2) est suspendue de telle sorte qu'elle peut pivoter autour d'un premier axe (7) et est agencée pour empêcher l'animal d'accéder à l'ouverture d'amenée (3) si la porte avant est dans un état fermé. La stalle comprend un dispositif de liaison déplaçable (9) reliant la porte avant (2) à la porte arrière (5) de sorte que l'ouverture, respectivement la fermeture, de l'une des portes force l'autre porte à se fermer, respectivement s'ouvrir. Le dispositif de liaison (9) comprend un élément élastique (10) pour un changement élastique de la longueur du dispositif de liaison (9). Par exemple, le dispositif de liaison comprend une tige télescopique élastique.</p></abstract><abstract mxw-id="PA101181405" ref-ucid="WO-2012136216-A1" lang="FR" source="national office" load-source="docdb"><p>L'invention concerne une stalle (1) pour animaux domestiques, de préférence des truies. La stalle comprend une porte avant (2) et une ouverture d'amenée (3) dans l'extrémité avant (4) de la stalle (1) et une porte arrière (5) à l'extrémité arrière de la stalle (6). La porte avant (2) est suspendue de telle sorte qu'elle peut pivoter autour d'un premier axe (7) et est agencée pour empêcher l'animal d'accéder à l'ouverture d'amenée (3) si la porte avant est dans un état fermé. La stalle comprend un dispositif de liaison déplaçable (9) reliant la porte avant (2) à la porte arrière (5) de sorte que l'ouverture, respectivement la fermeture, de l'une des portes force l'autre porte à se fermer, respectivement s'ouvrir. Le dispositif de liaison (9) comprend un élément élastique (10) pour un changement élastique de la longueur du dispositif de liaison (9). Par exemple, le dispositif de liaison comprend une tige télescopique élastique.</p></abstract><description mxw-id="PDES51855144" ref-ucid="WO-2012136216-A1" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="2"/>--><p id="p0001" num="0001"> A stall for domestic animals, preferably sows, with a resilient connecting rod Field of the Invention The present invention relates to a stall for domestic animals, preferably sows, as described hereinafter. The stall is configured and dimensioned to accommodate only one animal in the stall at a time. It comprises a front gate and a feed trough in the front end of the stall and a rear gate at the rear end of the stall. The front gate is suspended such that it can pivot about a first axis, for example, vertical axis, and arranged to prevent access by the animal to the feed trough if the front gate is in a closed state. The rear gate is suspended so that it can pivot about a second axis, for example, vertical or horizontal axis. The stall also includes a displaceable connection device that connects the front gate with the rear gate so that opening, respectively closing, of one gate forces the other gate to close, respectively open, as a result of a displacement of the connection. The invention also relates to the use of the displaceable connection for a stall for domestic animals. </p><p id="p0002" num="0002">Description of Related Art From European patent documents EP1333715, EP1346632 and EP2055183, Danish patent application DK2000 01216, German laid open documents DE2029600 and DE2528087, stalls for sows are known where the stall has a feed trough in the front end of the stall, and a front gate which, via a connection device, is connected to the rear gate so that opening the front gate causes closing of the rear gate, and opening the rear gate causes closing of the front gate. The rear gate is hinged horizontally and is, in open state, positioned above the animal's back. Such stalls are used in stable systems that are provided for free-moving flocks of sows. The feeding of free-moving sows in a stable takes place such that a flock of sows stays in an open area, after which the sows by themselves find an empty stall, where they by pushing to the front gate close the rear gate behind them. The sows can now eat undisturbed. This is further explained in the above-mentioned patent applications. Another disclosure to mention in this connection is Russian Patent application SU1316606, disclosing a stall with a front bar connected to rear gates via telescopic rods. 
<!-- EPO <DP n="3"/>-->
 Such stalls have a drawback. If a sow does not pres the front gate far enough ahead, the rear gate would not be completely closed. Thus, the locking system will not be able to secure the gate against opening caused by other sows that push their head under the gate. The result of a second sow's attempt to open the rear gate often results in breakage or bending of the brackets that keeps the gate in place. </p><p id="p0003" num="0003">It is therefore desirable to have a system that overcomes this disadvantage. </p><p id="p0004" num="0004">Description of the Invention </p><p id="p0005" num="0005">It is therefore the objective of the invention to remedy the above drawbacks. In particular, the objective is to prevent fracture of the bracket and suspension in the event that a sow is trying to push the rear gate upwardly, while another sow is in the stall. </p><p id="p0006" num="0006">This object is achieved by a stall for domestic animals, preferably sows, as described hereinafter. The stall is configured and dimensioned to accommodate only one animal in the stall at a time. It comprises a front gate and a feed trough in the front end of the stall as well as a rear gate at the rear end of the stall. The front gate is hung so that it can pivot about a first axis, for example horizontal or vertical axis, and arranged to prevent access by the domestic animal to the feed trough in the closed state of the front gate. The rear gate is suspended so that it can pivot about a second axis, for example vertical or horizontal axis. The stall also includes a displaceable connection device, connecting the front gate with the rear gate so that opening, respectively closing, of the one gate forces the other gate to close, respectively open, as a result of a displacement of the connection device. The connection device has a length between a first point, where the connection device is fastened to the front gate, and a second point, where the connection device is fastened to the rear gate. What is special about this stall is that the connection device comprises an elastic element for elastically changing the length of the connection device. 
<!-- EPO <DP n="4"/>-->
 The displacement of the connection device is in the direction between the first and the second point, and is mainly in its longitudinal direction, although a slight rotation or lateral displacement is often a part of the total movement during opening and closing of the gates. </p><p id="p0007" num="0007">Due to the elastic element in the connection device, the rear gate can be moved by a sow that is trying to get into a stall, without the brackets and mountings being overloaded. If the elastic element is compressible or stretchable so that the elastic force increases with the compression or stretching, the sow trying to come into the stall will experience a larger force, the more it presses against the gate, regardless of the gate giving in due to the pressure. Such a resilient element can, for example, be provided by a coil spring or a rubber element. </p><p id="p0008" num="0008">A connection device of variable length can be provided with profiles, which resiliently slide along each other. These profiles may, for example, be flat. Preferably, however, a connection device comprises a telescopic rod. Such a telescopic rod is provided with means for an elastic change in length of the telescopic rod. For example, the telescopic rod comprises a first and a second telescopic element that are slidable relatively to each other and resiliently connected by the elastic element. Such telescopic elements may, for example, be provided as hollow tubes or as a combination of a solid rod and a hollow tube. In addition, such a telescopic rod may also comprise more than two telescopic elements. </p><p id="p0009" num="0009">For example, the first telescopic element has a first end and the second telescopic element has a second end, and the elastic element, for example comprising a helical spring or elastomer or both, is provided between and abutting the first and second ends in order to counteract shortening of the telescopic rod. Alternatively, the telescopic rod can be configured such that the elastic element, for example comprising a helical spring or an elastomer or both, is provided between the first and second telescopic elements in order to counteract elongation of the telescopic rod. The latter can be of interest, if opening of the rear gate does not push the telescopic rod together but is connected to the telescopic rod such that it pulls the first and second telescopic elements apart. 
<!-- EPO <DP n="5"/>-->
 In a specific embodiment, the first telescopic element is a tube in which the elastic element is provided. The second telescopic element may then be a second tube or rod which is disposed partially within the first telescopic tube and in abutment with the elastic element. Preferably, the elastic element is a helical spring. </p><p id="p0010" num="0010">In a further embodiment there is provided a guide between the first and the second telescopic element. Advantageously, the guide includes an end stop which limits the variable length of the telescopic rod. For example, the guide includes an elongate groove in one of the two telescopic elements and a protrusion on the other of the two telescopic elements, the protrusion being in sliding co-operation with the elongate groove. Further, the elongated groove may have one or two end-stops that limit the movement of the protrusion in the elongate groove. </p><p id="p0011" num="0011">Advantageously, the telescopic rod may comprise the elastic element in a pre-tensioned state in order to counteract a change of the telescopic rod length. If there is disposed a coil spring in the first tube, as described above, such a spring can be pre-tensioned, as the end stop prevents the telescopic tube to obtain a length other than that defined by the end stop. Similarly, the elongate groove can have an opposite end stop to limit the shortening of the telescopic rod by compression of the elastic element, for example a helical spring, which then acts as a compression spring. </p><p id="p0012" num="0012">The elastic element may be provided in the connection device such that it counteracts either a shortening or a prolongation of the connection device. Alternatively, the elastic element may be provided in the connection device such that it counteracts a shortening as well as a prolongation of the connection device. In the latter case, the elastic element, for example, a rubber element or a coil spring, is generally not pre-tensioned. </p><p id="p0013" num="0013">As it appears from the above, a connection device with an elastic element to elastically change the length of the connection device, for example, an elastic telescopic rod, advantageously, can be used for the connection of a front gate and a rear gate of a stall for domestic animals, preferably sows. In particular, such a connection device as described above can be used for a stall configured and dimensioned to only accommodate one animal in the stall at a time, and comprising a front gate and a feed 
<!-- EPO <DP n="6"/>-->
 trough in the front end of the stall, and a rear gate at the stall rear, the front gate being hung so that it can pivot about a first axis, for example, vertical or horizontal axis and arranged to prevent access by the animal to the feed trough if the front gate is in a closed state; the rear gate is suspended so that it can pivot about a second axis, for example, vertical or horizontal axis; the telescopic rod then connects the front gate with the rear gate so that opening, respectively closing, of the one gate forces the other gate to close, respectively open, as a result of a displacement of the telescopic rod. </p><p id="p0014" num="0014">As shown above, such a stall can advantageously be used for free-moving sows, but the principle is equally applicable to other domestic animals, for example, horses, cows, or sheep. Preferably, the domestic animal is heavier than 10kg, whereby the invention is not used for small pets, like hamster and rabbits. </p><p id="p0015" num="0015">The first axis of the front gate and the second axis of the rear gate are typically vertical or horizontal, but it is also possible that the axes diverge at an angle of up to 45 degrees from the horizontal or vertical. Both axes can have the same direction or different direction. For example, both axes may be horizontal or vertical, or one axis may be horizontal and the other vertical. Combinations, where one or both of the axes having orientations which deviate from the horizontal or vertical are also possible. </p><p id="p0016" num="0016">Brief Description of the Drawing </p><p id="p0017" num="0017">The invention is described in greater detail with reference to the drawings in which FIG. 1 shows a stall according to the invention with a sow in the stall and a second so that tries to get access, </p><p id="p0018" num="0018"> FIG. 2 shows an empty stall, </p><p id="p0019" num="0019"> FIG. 3 shows an enlarged section of the connection device. Detailed Description of the Invention </p><p id="p0020" num="0020">FIG. 1 shows a stall according to the invention. The stall 1 comprises a front gate 2 and a feed trough 3 in the front end 4 of the stall 1, as well as a rear gate 5 at the rear 6 of the stall 1. The front gate 2 is mounted so that it can pivot about a vertical axis 7, 
<!-- EPO <DP n="7"/>-->
 and arranged to prevent access by the domestic animal to the feed trough 3 if the front gate is in a closed state. The rear gate 5 is suspended so that it can pivot about a horizontal axis 8. The stall 1 comprises a displaceable connecting device 9, which connects the front gate 2 with the rear gate 5 such that the opening, respectively closing, of the one gate forces the other gate to close, respectively open, as a result of a displacement of the connection device 9. The connection device has a length between a first point 10, where the connecting device 9 is fastened to the front gate 2, and a second section 11 where the connection device is fastened to the rear gate 5. In Figure 1, the stall 1 is shown with the rear gate 5 closed and the front gate 2 open. Due to the connection device 9, the front gate 2 is open when the rear gate 5 is closed and vice versa. When the rear gate 5 is open, and a sow enters a stall 1, the sow will try to reach the feed trough 3 in the front end 4 of the stall 1. In addition, it is necessary to open the front gate 2, which the sow accomplishes by pushing the front gate 2 with the snout, whereby the front gate is opened and the rear gate 5 is closed. Following the closure of the rear gate, the sow can eat undisturbed. </p><p id="p0021" num="0021">Sometimes, it happens that a sow feels unsafe during the opening of the front gate 2 and pulls back before the front gate 2 is fully opened. In order that a sow does not get jammed between the gate 2 and the side wall, the stall 1 is configured with a front gate 2 that does not extend over the entire width of the stall 1. The distance between the side wall and gate 2 is selected so that the sow may get its head between the gate 2 and the side wall, but not its shoulders. In this way, the sow cannot get its head caught between the gate 2 and the side wall. The lower edge of the frame of the front gate 2 is provided at a height such that a sow that lies down does not get its head caught under the front gate 2, if the sow happens to push against the rear gate 5. The stall is blocked in front with rods 25 to prevent the sow from leaving the stall this way. However, it is also possible that these rods 25 are replaced by a further gate so that the sow may leave the parlor 1 by this route. </p><p id="p0022" num="0022">FIG. 2 shows a side view, where a sow is in the stall 1 with its head by the feed trough 3. It is also illustrated that another sow tries to push the rear gate 5 upwards. This will normally result in the front gate 2 being closed. However, as the closing of the front 
<!-- EPO <DP n="8"/>-->
 gate 2 is not possible due to the presence of the sow at the trough in front, there may happen an overload of the bars and brackets, which leads to breakage or bending thereof. Typically, such happens if the sow in the front does not push the front gate 2 sufficiently forward for closing the rear gate completely and securing it by locking means, which are not further described here, but which for example is known from the above cited prior art. For example, the rear gate is pushed to a distance rearwardly to release it from the locking mechanism before the rear gate is transferred into a rotary motion in which it pivots upward. As a solution to the problem, there is provided a telescopic connecting device 9 with an elastic telescopic rod 12 having a first telescopic element in the form of a first tube 13 and a second telescopic element in the form of a second tube 14 that is partly pushed into the first tube 13. Between a first end 16 of the first tube 13 and a second end 15 of the second tube 14, there is provided a helical spring 17, as shown in the enlarged section of FIG. 2, in which the first pipe 13 is shown transparent for purposes of illustration. </p><p id="p0023" num="0023">When the rear gate 5 is pressed upwards, the rotation 18 of the rear gate 5 will provide a displacing force on the connection device 9, especially the rod 12, in the direction of the front gate 2. As the front gate 2 cannot be closed, the force will be absorbed by the helical spring 17 in the telescopic rod 12. As a result, the second tube 14 is pushed into the first tube 13 by compressing the helical spring 17, which counteracts the force applied to the rear gate 5 by the other sow. This protects the material and prevents breakage. The more the rear cover 5 is lifted, the more the helical spring 17 is compressed and the greater is the force that prevents the accidental lifting of the rear gate. As soon as the sow behind pulls back a little, the rear cover 5 closes again. </p><p id="p0024" num="0024">Under normal operating conditions, a sow with intension to leave the stall 1 will press the rear gate 5 rearwardly and thereby cause opening of the rear gate 5 with simultaneous closing of the front gate 2 by a displacement of the telescopic rod 12 in the direction towards the rear gate 5, which is illustrated by a double arrow 23 in FIG. 3. If the helical spring 17 in the telescopic rod 12 is sufficiently pre-tensioned, the telescopic rod 12 in such normal operating conditions is not compressed or only 
<!-- EPO <DP n="9"/>-->
 compressed very little, and will maintain a constant or approximately constant length during the closing and opening of the rear gate 5. Only in the above described and in FIG. 2 illustrated undesirable situation, where another sow is attempting to gain access to the stall, the attempt for opening causes a compression of the telescopic rod 12 if the latter's spring or other, alternative elastic element, has such a pre-tension. In this case, the other tube 14 is pushed farther into the first tube 13 </p><p id="p0025" num="0025">The change in length of the telescopic rod 12 during the compression is limited by the interaction of an elongated groove 20 in the first tube 13 with a protusion 19 of the second tube 14, where the protusion 19 is disposed in the elongate groove 20. As best illustrated in FIG. 2, the elongate groove 20 has a certain length with ends 21, 22, which function as end stops for the movement of the protusion 19 in the elongated groove 20. When the telescopic rod 12 is pushed together, the protusion 19 will move forward against the spring force until the protusion 19 reaches the forward end stop 22. Due to the pre-tension of the spring, the protrusion 19 will during normal use abut against the rear end stop 21 as illustrated in FIG. 3. The brackets 24 that connect the rear gate 5 with the frame 25 are sensitive to overload and are parts that are protected by the invention. 
</p></description><claims mxw-id="PCLM45499984" ref-ucid="WO-2012136216-A1" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><claim-statement><!-- EPO <DP n="10"/>-->Claims </claim-statement><claim id="clm-0001" num="1"><claim-text> 1. A stall (1) for domestic animals, the stall being configured for only accommodating one domestic animal in the stall at a time, the stall comprising a front gate (2) and a feeding trough (3) in the front end (4) of the stall (1) and a rear gate (5) at the rear end (6) of the stall, wherein the front gate (2) is suspended so that it can pivot about a first axis (7) and arranged to prevent access by the animal to the feeding trough (3) if the front gate is in a closed state, and wherein the rear gate (5) is suspended so that it can pivot about a second axis (8), and wherein the stall comprises a displaceable connection device (9) connecting the front gate (2) with the rear gate (5) such that the opening, respectively closing, of the one gate forces the other gate to close, respectively open, as a result of a displacement of the connecting device (9), wherein the connection device has a length between a first point (10), where the connecting device (9) is fastened to the front gate (2), and a second point (11), where the connecting device (9) is fastened to the rear gate (5), characterized in that the connection device (9) comprises an elastic element (17) for elastic change of the length of the connection device (9). </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0002" num="2"><claim-text>2. A stall according to claim 1, characterized in that the elastic element comprises a helical spring (17) or an elastomer or both. </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0003" num="3"><claim-text>3. A stall according to claim 2, characterized in that the elastic element comprises a helical spring (17). </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0004" num="4"><claim-text>4. A stall according to any preceding claim , characterized in that the connecting device (9) comprises a telescopic rod (12). </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0005" num="5"><claim-text>5. A stall according to claim 4, characterized in that the telescopic rod (12) comprises a first (13) and a second (14) telescopic element, which are slidable relatively to each other and resiliently connected by the elastic element (17). </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0006" num="6"><claim-text>6. A stall according to claim 5, characterized in that the first telescopic element (13) is a tube in which the elastic element (17) is provided. <!-- EPO <DP n="11"/>--> </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0007" num="7"><claim-text>7. A stall according to claim 5 or 6, characterized in that the first telescopic element (13) has a first end (16), and the second telescopic element (14) has a second end (15), and that the elastic element (17) is provided between the first end (16) and the second end (15) and in abutment with the first end (16) and the second end (15) to counteract a shortening of the telescopic rod (12). </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0008" num="8"><claim-text>8. A stall according to claim 5 or 6, characterized in that the elastic element is provided between the first and second telescopic elements and arranged for counteracting elongation of the telescopic rod. </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0009" num="9"><claim-text>9. A stall as claimed in all of claims 4-8, characterized in that there is provided a guide between the first (13) and second (14) telescopic element, the guide having an end stop (21,22) limiting the variable length of the telescopic rod (12). </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0010" num="10"><claim-text>10. A stall according to claim 9, characterized in that the guide comprises an elongated groove (20) in one of the two telescopic elements (13,14) and a protrusion (19) on the other of the two telescopic elements (14.13), wherein the protrusion (19) is in sliding co-operation with the elongate groove (20), wherein the elongate groove (20) has an end stop (21,22) limiting the movement of the protrusion (19) in the elongate groove (20). </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0011" num="11"><claim-text>11. A stall according to any one of the claims 3-10, characterized in that the telescopic rod (12) comprises the elastic element (17) in a pre-tensioned state in order to counteract a change of the length of the telescopic rod (12). </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0012" num="12"><claim-text>12. Use of a stall according to any one of claims 1-11 for free-moving sows. </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0013" num="13"><claim-text>13. Use of a telescopic rod (12) for connecting a front gate to a rear gate of a stall for domestic animals, wherein the telescopic rod (12) has an elastic element (17) for resilient change of the length of the telescopic rod (12). <!-- EPO <DP n="12"/>--> </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0014" num="14"><claim-text>14. Use according to claim 13, wherein the elastic element is a helical spring (17) or elastomer arranged for counteracting a compression of the telescopic rod. </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0015" num="15"><claim-text>15. Use according to claim 13, wherein the elastic element is a helical spring (17) or elastomer arranged for counteracting an elongation of the telescopic rod. </claim-text></claim></claims><copyright>User acknowledges that Fairview Research LLC and its third party providers retain all right, title and interest in and to this xml under applicable copyright laws.  User acquires no ownership rights to this xml including but not limited to its format.  User hereby accepts the terms and conditions of the Licence Agreement</copyright></patent-document>
